He is the co-founder of Tether
>> that the first generation stable coins
have is who gets the yield. It's these
centralized entities that are capturing
all the yield and it's extremely
lucrative and extremely profitable. The
promise of web 3 is that the people who
contribute to the ecosystem. The people
that use the product should reap the
rewards and the benefits. We have the
infrastructure now for the community to
reap all of the rewards. The solution is
to strip the yield, give it to the mtor,
and then spend the principal [music]
because the principal is also Genius Act
compliant. It's not a security. The
yield NFT is the security. That's what
[music] stable 2.0 is. Cuz a lot of
challenges with web 3 projects [music]
is that there's a lot of whales. It's
either the founders or the investors and
then they have to sell into that
community and it impacts the [music]
price. Well, we've created a really
elegant solution to that where
F1
Australian Grand Prix.
The most important guy in crypto is
sitting next to me. He is the co-founder
of Tether, ladies and gentlemen. Uh Ree
Collins. He's also the co-founder and
chairman of STBL and Weii. A lot to talk
about. Thank you for being here.
>> Absolutely. Thank you for having me. You
know what is crazy to me is in crypto we
have been using stable coins for a long
time and then institutions are just
catching up and then we're like uh yeah
we've been doing this for a long time
but you are looking at us and be like
well when I started it wasn't even a
category
>> which is crazy to me. What was the story
like? How do you even come up with the
concept that I'm going to put the dollar
on chain?
>> Yeah. Yeah. Yeah. Well, if you go back
10 plus years to 2013,
um, when when we first had this concept,
so back then there was just a couple of
cryptocurrencies, Bitcoin, Litecoin,
Dogecoin, I mean, just a handful. Yeah.
And and Bitcoin was this fascinating new
type of foreign currency, but uh it was
based in code, right? So, people didn't
really understand it, but it was this
new currency. But what was really
interesting was how it moved. It moved
globally, instantly, and for free. And
so while not a lot of people wanted to
trade Bitcoin, the the utility, the
functionality of it was pretty
incredible. And so that's where the idea
came up. It's like, oh, let's put the
dollar on the blockchain. Let's enable
dollars, euros, yen to move globally
instantly and for free. Wouldn't that be
amazing? Wouldn't it be amazing if
anyone in the world could get a dollar
that didn't have a bank account? And so
that really was the impetus of it. And
so back in 2013, we we kind of had the
idea really launched it in 2014. And the
first real use cases and this obviously
there wasn't a name stable coin. I don't
even know when that category came out.
Probably not even until 2015 or 16 when
people actually started saying, "Oh,
it's a stable coin." Um,
>> but we created USDT and and the
exchanges used it at first because
they're the ones that really needed to
move money. So, they moved the money
amongst them. Then the traders used it
because they wanted a stable pair to to
trade Bitcoin against. And then
eventually it started more and more
people started using it because it was a
better way to move money. So that's the
the the the quick history of the origin
of it. And now today that concept right
the ability to move money
>> globally instantly for free um has
become the the foundation of the entire
cryptocurrency ecosystem
>> and and finally now that the regulatory
winds are at our back and and and the
road is being paved the institutions are
finally getting involved. They're like,
"All right, yes, this is much more
efficient. This is much better
technology to move our money with. So,
let's figure out how to play in this
world."
>> It feels like I'm watching a documentary
on the history of this thing, but you
are the main actor in it and you are I'm
imagining you just said we decided or we
planned. Do you sit at a dinner table
and be like, "We want to move money
freely." How does that work? I'm trying
to imagine
>> the idea came up and then I was the CEO.
So as a co-founder and CEO and I created
this and so I really led the charge in
the beginning and really um I had two
co-founders at the time uh main
co-founders there was Brock Pierce and
Craig Sers um and then some principles
from Bitfinex got involved and then they
eventually took it over and that's we
sold that company to them and then and
then really call it 2017 when the when
the ICO boom hit the world. That's when
Tether really took off. But those guys
are really responsible for the meteoric
rise of Tether. We put it all together,
built all the technology, but the the
the real momentum didn't start until
2017 on um because that's when the world
really was starting was was ready for it
because now a thousand new coins hit the
scene with the advent of the ICO. Um so
yeah it was uh you know an extraordinary
contribution to the ecosystem was to to
deliver the stable coin and now today
what's next what are the big issues with
stable coins there's two main issues the
main one uh or the first one is the
backing. So a lot of the FUD that you
hear, a lot of the issues is like, oh,
is Tether really backed? Are do these
stable coins really have the money in
the bank to back them? And so we've
solved that with stable coin 2.0. So all
the collateral now can be onchain
>> because treasuries back the majority of
stable coins, but now that treasuries
are tokenized, you can now use a
tokenized treasury to back the stable
coin. Now that's tokenized, it's
onchain. So now we have the ability to
have 100% of the collateral onchain. So
you have transparency 24/7 knowing that
the collateral is there and it matches
the amount of stable coin in in
circulation.
Secondly, the other challenge that the
first generation stable coins have is
who gets the yield. It's these
centralized entities that are capturing
all the yield and it's extremely
lucrative and extremely profitable
because they're just sitting on your
money while you while you use it. Um and
that's also why all the institutions
that's why everyone's launching stable
coin because there's a lot of profit to
be made.
But we need to fix that because the
promise of web 3 is that the people who
contribute to the ecosystem, the people
that use the product should reap the
rewards and the benefits because we now
have the technology to do that. That
technology is wallets and tokens. And so
in a web 3 company that has a token
where the value from that community
should acrue to. Well, that's what
stablecoin 2.0 is. It enables the
community to reap the rewards because
now when you put that collateral on
chain and you mint the stable coin, we
strip the yield into a second token and
now that community member, the person
who put the money into there, he's the
one that gets the yield and then a small
fee goes to the ecosystem which then
goes into the token. And so with this
decentralized technology of STBL, we
have the infrastructure now for the
community to reap all of the rewards.
>> Earlier you were talking about tokenized
T bills. Why can't all the larger
issuers do that already?
>> Well, so this is why we've coined
Stablecoin 2.0 that solve these two
issues, putting the collateral on chain
and giving the yield to the users
because STBL might not be the company
that wins in the end. I firmly believe
it will because we're the first, but I
believe it's a movement that we've
created because now that all the
collateral can be on the chain like you
just said, well, why aren't they doing
it? I believe they will. And now that we
have a mechanism to provide yield to the
users in a Genius Act compliant way,
that's probably too much detail for
this, but in in a very compliant ways. I
believe everyone will also do that
because if you're a user and you want to
put money in the system, you might as
well get rewarded for it and you might
as well have complete transparency of
the backing. So I think that these
tenants um will be what is the future of
stable coins. I think other companies
are going have to be fast followers.
>> I think what you're referring to is one
of the rules that the yield should not
be shared to the users in the Genius
Act. Is that what you're referring to?
>> So yes, Gen the Genius Act does not
allow for yield bearing stable coins.
Right. So yield bearing stable coins
were the first solution to how do you
share yield with users.
>> There's two challenges with a yield
bearing stable coin. One, it's an NFT.
I'm sorry. One, it's a security
>> and and two, it's uh non-compliant in
the US when the Genius Act rolls out,
>> but three, and most importantly, it
becomes an investment. Now, you're
earning 2 or 3% on your cash, but you
have to sit on it. You have to sit on
that stable coin and earn it. Wouldn't
you rather be able to earn that yield
and spend the stable coin,
>> right? Because if you mint it right now,
let's say you give $10,000 of USDC.
Well, USDC, the company is making the
yield on your 10 grand while you're
spending it. But instead of allowing
USDC to be the issuer, why don't you
mint the $10,000 of UST and you keep the
yield. So now you keep the yield and
spend it. And so that's why the yield
bearing stable coin isn't the solution.
The solution is to strip the yield, give
it to the mtor, and then spend the
principle because the principle is also
Genius Act compliant. It's not a
security. The yield is the the yield NFT
is the security.
>> Can I know what is the difference
between this design and Athena? I know
that their yield is from um different
strategies. Of course, it's very
different, but the layered token concept
is that the same?
>> No. So, when we started stable,
everyone's like, why are you doing
another stable coin? Because there's
lots of stable coins coming out. So
unless you do something significantly
different and at least 10 times better,
then there's no point in joining a meto
movement, right? So so that's why we've
evolved the stable coin. And so it's not
like Athena. Um Athena is is a great
company. The way they generate yield is
super unique and novel and and powerful,
but still it's it's a yield bearing
stable coin. You get the yield by
holding the token. Like we split the
yield and so you get to spend it.
>> I see. So our yield is generated from
treasuries and money market funds within
the US for the Genius Act compliant
portion and then non US let's we we're a
stablecoin infrastructure
we have a product called ESS which is
ecosystem specific stable coin which is
a fancy word for a white label stable
coin so we offer institutions and
governments and large organizations the
ability to mint their own stable coin.
>> Okay. Um, and the reason why that's so
powerful is because then they get to
choose the backing. So, Athena has its
yield bearing uh or yield mechanisms.
Um, our Genius Act compliant is backed
by treasuries and money market funds.
But if you're in the rest of the world
and you don't want to use treasuries,
you want to use like credit or different
types of um assets to to back it, you
can get 5 to 10% instead of 2 to 4%. and
and it's still just as safe and just as
liquid, but it's just higher yielding.
So, in the future, these big
corporations or people who are minting
can utilize other RWAs
as backing for the as collateral for the
stable coin because another big
narrative right now is RWAS. All these
traditional assets are coming on chain,
but when they come on chain, they're
still the same as the traditional asset.
They just have the characteristics of
being on chain, you know, a lot more
liquid, easier to use, available 24/7,
etc. But it's still the same. However,
being on chain now increases the utility
of it.
>> Meaning, if there's more utility, that
means more yield. And the main way to
increase the utility of an RWA is by
utilizing it as backing for a stable
coin. So that using RWAS's as backing in
the case of a stable coin is going to be
the killer app, the killer use case for
especially onchain treasuries and other
high quality assets that are being
tokenized. So that's going to drive more
and more traditional assets to being
tokenized is because they can be used as
collateral for stable coins. We have a
lot of different stable coins already,
but I think it feels like people are
more used to the ones that are being
backed by very liquid and of course they
say cash or short-term tea bills. If I
I'm trying to picture this world where
my stable coin is being backed by real
estate, a piece of real estate or
whatever in Dubai, then I I would not
feel as secure.
>> Yes. And it's a great point, but there's
a wide range of RWAs coming on chain
between T bills and and and real estate.
>> But let's use your example of real
estate. I believe in the future at some
point
>> there will be baskets backing the stable
coins. And so let's say you have a
million dollars worth of real estate and
you you you're sitting on it tokenized.
Maybe the LTV, the loan to value, maybe
you can get 20% of it as backing for
stable. It's a massive haircut. So you
put a million dollars and they're like,
"Oh, we'll give you $200,000 worth of
credit." And there'll be a lot of
mechanisms to ensure that's very liquid.
Um so those th those type of structures
will be coming in the future and you
will be comfortable. You're like okay
fine yes it's backed by this massive
basket but here's a lot of math that
proves that those assets are liquid
enough to ensure that the stable coin is
backed.
>> So it's not an algorithmic stable coin.
>> Oh yeah. It it has hard asset backing um
with just different formulas for how
much of that asset you can use to back
the stable coin.
>> Should we come up with different names
for different types of stable coins? Cuz
for a lot of newbies that come into
crypto, they're like, "Oh, it's all
called stable coin. So, the risk behind
it should be the same." But it's not.
>> Well, but there are different names. So
stable coins is a category but there's
asset back stable coins and there's uh
algorithmic stable coins and there's
hybrids and delta neutral hedging
strategy stable coins which is Athena
you know so so there are lots of
different ways to back the stable coin
and the user gets to decide what makes
the most sense for him and this is where
in the future large institutions and
companies and enterprises they will have
their own money they will issue their
own branded currency, right? And their
ecosystem will be comfortable with
whatever backing that that company is
putting out there and because that
company's going to guarantee that that
the backing is always is always uh
redeemable one to one to the dollar and
and that company might back it with
something specific that makes sense to
them because they have a community that
trusts them and will use that as a
currency. And if it's built on top of
STBL,
that means that they've minted USST
and and so when it's in their ecosystem,
it will be backed specifically by their
backing and follow their rules, but only
that ecosystem might accept that stable
coin. But if that user wants to take it
out, they can instantly swap it for USST
and then uh and then spend that
everywhere else. Earlier you were
talking about how you know stable coin
issuers their margin is sounds like it's
going uh slimmer compared to what it
used to be. How they trap all the
revenue right um but that is the reason
why traditional finance are talking
about stable coin issuers is because
they make crazy amount of money. They
are attracted to that. But what happens
when it becomes something that is
in their view less profitable? I don't
know if it's necessarily because they
make crazy amounts of money, right? That
the the massive ones do because they
have massive amounts of money uh that
that's that's generating still a very
low amount of yield um proportionately,
>> but it's the power and and and all these
big companies are interested in it
because of the utility. Like moving from
fiat or from cash into stable coin rails
enables you to move money globally,
instantly for free. It enables you to
move money to everyone, anyone who wants
to opt into this type of system. It's a
much more efficient way to move money.
So, if you think about the future and
where we're going, um
because a lot of people think, well,
what if stable coins is stable coin
going to replace the dollar? The stable
coin is a dollar. It's just formatted
differently, right? So, stable coins are
still backed by fiat currency. Fiat
currency will always have its place in
this world. It's just that this is a
more efficient and better way to move
that fiat currency. It's just like prior
to sending emails, you wrote a letter.
Pretty inefficient. Now sending emails,
super efficient. Prior to stable coins,
you used the bank. Pretty inefficient.
For some countries, really inefficient
or not even accessible, right? But now
you have blockchain, which is super
efficient. Now that the large
institutions can utilize blockchain
technology because of regulation, they
will. I believe that as much fiat money,
as much traditional money that can flow
into stable coins, it will because these
big companies would like to push all of
their money into their brand of stable
coin because it creates more profit as
you said, but also a lot more
efficiencies and ease of use and utility
for them. companies like Walmart or big
retail um companies they are exploring
their own stable coin but I am guessing
this is my assumption that they want to
trap the value within their own
ecosystem for example if you get paid in
their own stable then maybe I can use
that stable to pay for ad services for
example is this assumption correct are
we heading to a world where every large
company has their own stable coin, but
then the liquid aspect of stable coin is
gone if everyone has their own little
ecosystem.
>> It's an excellent observation and I
couldn't agree with you more that all
large companies are going that way. I
believe for sure that these companies
are going to start issuing their own
stable coins because yes,
>> right now, you used Walmart as an
example, tens of billions of dollars
flow through the Walmart ecosystem,
right? They play people globally around
the world, suppliers, vendors,
customers, everything. All this money
flows around. But it's cash. Walmart not
only doesn't earn any money on that
cash, they pay a lot of fees to move
that cash, especially if they need to
exchange it into different currencies
around the world. If they could just
create Walmart coin backed by dollars
and every vendor in the world accepted
it, think of the efficiencies they would
have. Not only the efficiencies, in
addition the fact that now that Walmart
coin is there's tens of billions of
dollars of Walmart and people are using
the token now they're getting yield
interest on that tens of billions of
dollars of Walmart coin.
>> Your next question was okay now if that
ecosystem has its own currency and this
one has its own currency and this one
has its own currency
>> there there will be clearing houses to
make those interchangeable and swappable
and fungeable, right? and and what's
going to make those transactions easy
because this all sounds complicated,
right? Blockchain and crypto and stable
coins and the 25
uh different L1s out there. It is
complicated. Do you want do you want
USDT on Ethereum or on TON? People don't
need to know that stuff in the future
because AI is going to run the
transactions for them. And so if there's
hundreds of different stable coins and
you've got Walmart coin and I've got
Amazon coin, like we're not going to
care. All I care about is I get a
dollar's worth of value and you get a
dollar's worth of value and the AI is
going to do all of that interchange and
all the complex stuff in the background.
Like it's not going to matter what's
under the hood.
>> So what I'm seeing is the same thing but
just underneath the surface it's
different companies
>> because all you're going to care about
is moving some value to someone doing a
transaction. You're not going to care
which blockchain or which token or which
anything.
>> Absolutely. Yeah.
>> Everyone cares about it now for two
reasons. This past decade, people have
made so much money on the
infrastructure. Do you think anyone
really cares how an L1 blockchain works?
No. It's super complicated. It's the
most complicated areas of finance and
cryptography that there is.
>> No one cares except for they want to
invest in it because they see people
making lots of money. So now they want
to understand it. No one understands how
an email works and no one cares because
no one's making money. If you're making
a tons of money on HTTP and TCIP and all
that stuff, you might want to understand
how it works, but no one's making money,
so they don't care. This is the exact
same thing, but everyone cares
>> because there's tokens and they're
making money.
>> But now it's been a decade that that
infrastructure is being laid. We're
finally getting to the application layer
where more and more people are now are
going to compare are going to care about
the transactions and not necessarily
which chain it goes on. Um and so I see
I think a lot of the focus will be on
real world use cases on top of
blockchains and at the moment it's the
movement of money but but soon there'll
be more and more and more uh use cases
being built on top of it. For instance,
Weii is is the evolution of banking. So
in the beginning there's banking and
there's neo banking which is banking
without a storefront. It's just online
banking and now there's onchain banking
and there's a lot of companies offering
onchain banking services. So what makes
it unique? Well, Weii is unique in the
sense that it's delivering on the
promise of Web 3 because it's driven by
a token and this token rewards all of
the community members. So, when they
when they transact and do and and
utilize the financial services that Weii
provides, all those fees get recycled
back into that token and and that
community is rewarded. And we've created
a really unique structure where all of
the tokens are owned by the community
because a lot of challenges with web 3
projects is that there's a lot of
whales. It's either the founders or the
investors and then they have to sell
into that community and it impacts the
price. Well, we've created a really
elegant solution to that where that
token is only generated and given to the
community and then there's equity value.
So the equity value gets paid for
delivering world-class financial
services. the community gets paid for
using the world-class financial
services. And so that's what enables our
financial services to be differentiated
from someone else's because ours is much
more community oriented and and when
they're utilizing it, the token value
goes up and they're all the the the the
beneficiary owners of that token. And so
this is truly a company that's that
creates these financial services for its
community. Can I know the difference
between this and other web 3 banks that
are competing crazily out there right
now? They have their own token and they
offer onchain financial services as
well. There has to be something that is
special.
>> One, a lot of these NEO banks or even
some of these other onchain banks, um,
if they don't have their token, then the
community doesn't really get much of a
reward. if they do have a token, we are
the only ones where the community is the
only one that has the token. 100% of
that token value stays within the
community and all of the fees and
everything um reward those token holders
because they're contributing. They're
using the financial services. There's
equity holders. So, we have two
ecosystems. And the reason why it's so
important for the equity holders is the
equity holders get their value by
creating world-class financial services.
When we create great financial services
and more people use it, then the equity
is worth more. When more people use it,
the token's worth more. So, we've
actually created a very synergistic
flywheel that rewards the people that
should be rewarded, which are the
founders and investors as well as the
community. Cuz in the past and until
now, the community is never rewarded.
The community is typically rewarded with
the utilization of a product. Think
about Facebook or any traditional
product like a company. the the users of
it get entertainment value, get some
utility, get something out of it, but
they don't get financially rewarded.
That's what we've finally solved and I
we've solved it in a very elegant manner
where both the equity is worth something
and the tokens are worth something
without any whales trying to sell into
the community.
>> I think you just brought us something
really interesting. So when I explain
these tokens to beginners, a lot of
times I use this analogy of a startup or
like a new company or a tech company and
owning the token means you're owning a
piece of it. But you brought up the
equity side and the token side. Now can
I dumb it down for me? If the equity
goes up, does that equal to the token
should go up as well? It depends on why
the equity goes up, right? So the equity
in in a company like this would go up
the larger the community is. The larger
the community is, the more the token
goes up. So that's a synergistic
flywheel. In traditionally in a lot of
companies, if the token goes up and the
founders and investors own 50% of the
tokens and it goes up, they're going to
start selling and selling and selling
and they have massive amounts of float
to sell. Um, in this instance, it's all
the community holders and and there's no
one that that was given, you know, 10 20
30 40 50% of the of the token. I'm not
saying these other models don't work at
all, but in this instance, it's just a
really elegant solution because in a lot
of those other models,
>> there is no equity value. It's just
token value. So, I'm not discount
because um stable is all about the token
value, right? And and me as a founder of
stable uh I have tokens, right? And so
you still can do it responsibly, but
we've with WeFi, it's a really elegant
solution where you can have this
services business where you're providing
financial services and and how do you
compete with other people that are pro
providing financial services is you have
a token that truly rewards the community
without fear of whales dumping. Is this
going to be like a parallel system to
the financial traditional banking system
or do you see everybody moving towards
that direction?
>> 100% I see everyone moving towards that
direction because what that direction is
is simply financial services
>> done in a hybrid manner. Meaning again
all you want to do is transact in USD or
some other currency or whatever it is
that you might want to transact in or
crypto but you want to go to one place
and have all those things and so soon
large traditional financial institutions
will enable you to transact with crypto
soon I don't know when but in like the
really large ones might take a very long
time but they'll I would I know for a
fact very soon there'll be a lot of
financial institutions that enable you
to transact with dollars or with crypto
and for instance we will also allow you
to transact with fiat currency. Think
about what a stable coin is. It it it's
a token backed by a dollar that moves on
the blockchain. Soon that's going to be
reversed. You're going to have a dollar
backed by a token. And so that dollar
will still move on the blockchain
because now the token is going to be
what moves, but you're going to see a
dollar in your account. It's just going
to move on a blockchain. Whereas before,
you saw a token in your account that
moved on a blockchain. And so once you
got that token, you had to convert it to
a dollar if you wanted to. that's soon
going to switch where you're just going
to get a dollar and even though it moved
on a blockchain, you don't care, right?
You just wanted the dollar.
>> How is the traditional like the Swift
system or Visa Mastercard reacting to
this?
>> I mean, I feel they're all much more
open to exploring it and trying to
figure out how to best participate in
it. Mhm.
>> Um those massive traditional companies,
they have so many layers of regulation
and then bureaucracy, they're they're
just slow slow moving beasts by design
because of how they've evolved over the
decades. Um so it's very hard for them
to be innovative. So they can be
disruptive, but all of them
>> do have departments dedicated towards
crypto and trying to figure out a
strategy and trying to figure out how to
participate. Look at PayPal. It's not
this old financial institution, but they
actually rolled out a stable coin. Even
though they rolled out a stable coin
with all of their adoption and
everything, it's still struggling to to
get um uh real utilization. There's a
number of reasons for that that we won't
get into, but it's just a great example
that that they're really leaning in. And
Visa, Mastercard, Amics, all of them
have announced initiatives in the crypto
space. So, they're all trying to figure
out how to to stay relevant because they
can easily be replaced if if they're
not.
>> They already have all the relationships,
the networks. Can't they just come up
with something and
>> yeah,
>> take over the whole market?
>> They're trying,
>> but they're not. It's not really
happening. And I'm I'm just wondering
why.
>> I think you underestimate when I say
layers of bureaucracy and layers of
regulation
>> how stifling that is to innovation. Mhm.
>> So, it's not that they don't want to.
It's not that they don't have super
smart people in there. It's just uh they
they have a lot of obstacles that
startup companies don't.
>> But on the flip side, they have tons of
money and tons of customers that startup
companies don't. So, who's going to win
that race? We'll see. I I don't know.
>> When you talk about this, it's more like
a vision and you seem like you can see
very far ahead of future. But if we talk
about what's happening now with all the
bills, legislation, all the boring
stuff, what do you think when people say
stable coin is the US government trying
to save its debt problem?
>> Stable coin is a big category and is the
proliferation of this category and the
fact that there's now a new category, a
new customer to the US government, that
customer is stable coin issuers. That's
why the US government said it has to be
Genius Act compliant, meaning you can
only back a stable coin by US dollars.
And so anyone who wants to operate a
stable coin that's except in the US will
be backed by US dollars. But I also
believe stable coins the rest of the
world will will be backed by other
things as well because they're higher
yielding um other types of financial
instruments.
And is the government trying to solve
its debt? I don't think it can solve its
all its problems just because there's
one extra customer buying a couple
hundred billion dollars of treasuries.
Their problem it's great and it's a
right step in it's a step in the right
direction and I'm and it's great to see
the the government leaning in and paying
a lot of attention to it. But it I mean
I I can't even comment. It's such a
complex issue to solve, but I think it's
it's just an excellent use case for
treasuries. That's for sure. and the
backing is going to expand beyond that
as well.
>> What do you say to
countries that are so not ready and so
far behind when it comes to stable coins
>> that that it's coming and that a large
percentage of their population in those
countries um are utilizing them in in
some way or shape or form and maybe a
large percentage of their population is
overstating it. I always get asked how
big is the market, how many people are
using stable coins and in crypto and to
me everybody. But I know that that's not
true, right? I just kind of wish it was
and in my world it seems like it because
that's that's where I exist. But as the
ease of use and access to crypto and
stable coins and this is what Weii is
trying to drive, trying to create a
really elegant, easy to use for end
users solution to to crypto and better
banking experience. Um, as that becomes
more and more common, more and more
people will utilize it and those
countries their their regulations
ideally will catch up.
I have a question. When it [music] comes
to smaller African countries with crazy
inflation, what they do is they try to
trap their own currency inside their own
system. What happens if stable coin is
so common, these very weak currencies?
Do do they just all of a sudden
disappear and everyone start using
stronger currencies?
>> Well, let's put it this way. If it was
up to the citizens of those countries,
then yes, their their their local
government's currency would disappear.
is if it's up if it's up to the
government, they're going to fight to
the death to not allow that to happen.
So, it just depends on how good they are
at stifling that revolution, but all
they can do is try to put a lid on it,
and they can't stop it. And and the
people are going to figure out ways
around it because they're going to want
a more stable currency. That's what's
driven a lot of the global adoption for
stable coins is because the invention of
the stable coin democratized access to
US dollars. A lot of the countries that
you're talking about would love US
dollars. They never had the ability to
have access to them before and now they
do simply with an internet connection.
And so for the government to truly shut
that down very hard.
>> Some of the countries are exploring
a stable coin that is within their own
country. It's not like a US dollar
stable coin where it's free flowing.
>> Yeah.
>> Um it's sometimes it's due to the
culture. It's due to policy.
How does that h how does that change
when you picture the future and the
landscape of stable coin?
Do we get different stable coins in all
different countries? Some are open, some
are closed. How how does that work?
>> I believe that there'll be lots and lots
and lots of flavors of stable coins.
>> Um and again, there'll be some clearing
house where where those stable coins can
be exchanged unless it's a country that
says because it's also programmable.
that country might say no this token
cannot be swapped or exchanged or used
in anything other than these whitelisted
wallets right so it's really going to
depend on the policy of and and the
rules put in place for that particular
token
>> I am very curious how do you look at the
world because you're always so early on
things
>> which isn't always a good thing um you
know sometimes you're too early but uh I
will say I look at it with a slightly
optimistic view right I I like to we can
all be optimistic or pessimistic and I'm
an entrepreneur at heart and to be an
entrepreneur and to start businesses you
just have to believe they're going to
work and if you're pessimistic you
probably aren't going to believe the
crazy ideas are actually going to work
and so when I say when you ask how do I
view the world I do view the world as
embracing this technology and I view
some governments accelerating the
adoption and some governments trying to
stifle the adoption but I also firmly
believe that they can't stifle it
forever there the the best analogy I use
is Uber. When Uber came out, it was
essentially illegal in a lot of places,
but the people demanded it. It was such
a good service. Once that genie was out
of the bottle, once people experienced
it, both the drivers and the customers
were like, "This is a hundred times
better than taxis and it provides jobs
for everyone." The protests when they
banned it, right, there's protests to
ban it from the taxi companies and
there's protests to unban it after they
banned it and and eventually Uber's
ubiquitous, right? So this is kind of
the same which is some countries are
going to stifle it but the people are
just going to demand it right because
it's it's a better financial
infrastructure on a global level and it
plugs every person in the world into the
same structure whereas before there you
were very siloed into your country but
now you have a a global solution um and
so I I I really don't think it can be
stopped it can be slowed down which it
has been but u but it's coming right and
at the end of the day Who wins? The
people. They have better financial
services, better ways to do business,
better currencies, better ways to earn
money. Imagine people that never had the
ability to do a $10 investment before.
$10 is a lot of money to them, but no
one could do investment. But but now
those types of products and services are
coming. People will be able to do these
micro investments and and make a little
bit of money to us, but a whole lot of
money to them. It's it's it's an amazing
thing. The challenges when it comes to
real world asset now is how do you
verify that this token actually
represents this actual asset and I think
a lot of people are trying to solve that
how far away are we are is it very close
>> well it depends um it's a great insight
and that's where regulation comes into
play because right now it's trust me bro
here's a token the money's there when
it's regulated it's trust me but if I'm
lying to do I go to jail? Those are the
differences, right? Um and so and so
that's where regulation really comes in
and that's why I think these large
institutions and why a lot of the
population will then be attracted
towards more regulated stable coins and
cryptocurrencies is because they can
trust them a little bit more.
>> We we imagine this world where you know
a Kenyan farmer can now invest $10 into
let's say a Taiwanese stock TSMC one of
the biggest uh chip maker. But that
seems very far away because of
legislation. It's not that the technical
side can't be done, but it's all the
countries or governments trying to
protect their own system. What you're
saying is people are going to demand
that.
>> Yes. And
>> well well said. I that's
>> I am just trying to picture how early
you are on this and I'm like huh is this
10 years or is this three years
>> we don't know
>> but I feel progress is inevitable
>> and again you can slow it down but but
but with my optimistic view I don't
think you can stop it and I and I hope
you don't and I hope that some
governments will embrace it and offer
this and then when other governments see
that these people have done it and
they've done it responsibly then there
are people will demand it. It's also the
debate around CBDC's. Everyone says, "Is
it a good thing or a bad thing?" Mike,
it depends on which hat you have. If you
have the government's hat on, it's the
best thing in the world. If you have the
citizens hat on, their freedoms are
restricted and controlled and their
currencies are even more controlled than
they were before. Will governments roll
them out? If they can, they will. If
they can't because the people they
there's a more of a democracy and they
can't get away with it, they won't. You
know this is eyeopening because I talked
to a lot of lawmakers in Asia and a lot
of them are talking about this because
it's on the news and because it's after
circle went IPO it's such a huge thing
because the traditional finance now care
about it but I think it is so much
bigger than that and they should really
listen to this episode.
>> I I hope so. I I would love to have you
back later in the future. Maybe talk
more about your ideology because I find
it really interesting.
>> No, I I' I'd be happy to. Yeah, thanks
for the questions. And you do have a
great insight into the market and where
it's going and and look, I just believe
in this technology. I believe in
delivering on the promise of blockchain.
So, the the the the democratization of
access to to dollars or to better
currencies and to better financial in
infrastructure and systems. And then web
3, right? we have the technology now to
reward the community, to reward the
people that are putting money into
whatever ecosystem they're participating
in. And so I want to see more and more
companies delivering on that promise.
And and that's why I enjoy these
conferences and talking about it because
the more people realize what the
potential is, then then the more they'll
dive in and the more that inevitable
future that I believe is coming will
happen sooner rather than later.
>> Or you can just chill at home and people
will demand it.
>> That's right. A little slower though.
>> Yeah.
>> Thank you so much for your time.
>> Pleasure.